PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- So, when I was in elementary school,
- 嗯 当我还在小学的时候
I mean, I studied math like everybody else,
我和其他人一样学习数学
the sorta basics that we learned at school,
就是那些我们在学校学到的最基础的东西
and found that there's something about it
我发现了一些
which it was greater than I am.
比我本人更加伟大的东西
It wasn't that one person had decided
那并不是一个人决定了
that this is how it was gonna be,
事物是如何发展的
it was more that, collectively, we'd kind of slowly come to
更多的是 我们大家一起慢慢地
a better understanding of something
对一直都存在的东西
that has always been there.
有了更深刻的理解
And so, I really appreciated
我也十分感激
and kind of was in awe of that idea.
我能敬畏这种想法
And at the same time, I was playing a lot of music,
在那段时间里 我也弹奏了不少音乐
I think, as a young kid,
我想 作为一个年轻的孩子
and fascinated in how our ear
陶醉于我们的耳朵
and our brain and our mind works,
大脑和心智是如何工作的
given all of this kinda stimulus coming in.
让我有了点点思考的火花
So, for me, it was kind of a natural meeting
对于我而言 两种世界的交汇
of these two worlds.
是一个自然的过程
A little bit of math and a little bit of perception,
一点数学加上一点直观感受
you smash 'em together, and you kinda land in color science.
你把它们混在一起 就进入了色彩科学的大门
Before I started working in motion picture film,
在我为动画电影工作之前
I did some challenging,
我做了一些极具挑战
some people would say some silly things. (laughs)
有些人会认为是傻帽的事情（笑）
I used to engage in a lot of mountaineering,
我当时热衷于登山
high-altitude climbing.
高海拔攀登
And on one of these expeditions at high altitude,
在一次高海拔探险中
I suffered an injury to the retina on my left eye.
我的左眼视网膜受了伤
It's a retinal hemorrhage.
视网膜出血
So, basically, the retina was bleeding and became damaged.
简单来说 就是视网膜出血和损伤
And it wasn't painful, but during the process,
它并不是很疼 但在这个过程中
I was completely fascinated
我完全惊讶于
with what was happening to my visual system.
我的视觉系统所发生的一切
I was able to sort of see, oh, well something's not right
我时不时能看见 嗯 有些东西不太对
and this is different and new.
和以前不一样 是全新的
And then I was able to compare,
然后我就可以对比
well, my left eye is different to my right eye.
我左眼和右眼的不一样
And if I kinda move my head this way,
如果我像这样移动脑袋
I can see these weird things I've never seen before.
我就能看到以前没见过的奇怪事物
And so, it was a weird sense of kind of objective analysis
那是一种奇怪的客观分析
of what was going on, despite the fact that it was,
到低发生了什么的感受 而不是意识到
in some senses, a medical emergency.
这就是一场事故这个事实的感受
And we were far away from hospitals
现在我们早已远离医院
and those kinds of things.
和那些事情
But that was probably one of the turning points
但那些事情就是众多拐点中的一个
where I recognized that, wow, I'm really interested
让我意识到 原来我对人类的视觉系统
in the human visual system and what it can and can't do.
和它能或不能干什么那么有兴趣
And, hopefully, we're using that now
我们也希望现在我们所做的一切
in a way that's gonna help everybody.
能帮助到每个人
Computer systems engineering
计算机系统工程学
is the primary degree I studied.
是我的主要专业
Engineering is less about the specific knowledge
工程学不太是了解一个特定的知识
and more about knowing how to learn at speed.
更像是明白如何快速的学习
So, a good portion of the degree
所以 这个专业的一个好处是
is stress testing your ability to learn things
它强调测试你学习
you've never thought of before
从未思考过的东西
and then really put your assumptions to the test in a hurry.
并将你的猜想付诸实验的能力
So, I consider the engineering kinda like a mixed bag
所以我认为工程学就像一大包工具
of tools that can be applied
可以用在
to a lotta different circumstances.
各种繁杂的状况下
When I started with Pixar,
当我刚开始在皮克斯时
35-millimeter film was still
35 毫米胶片依旧
very much the predominant distribution format.
是很主要的发布格式
You know, we used film projectors.
你明白 我们用胶片投影机
You had a xenon lamp and it shown light
你有一个氙气灯 它将光线投射过
through a transparency, a color transparency,
胶片正片 彩色正片
up onto a huge screen.
打到一张巨大的荧幕上
The chemistry of the color of film
胶片色彩的化学机制
was very much a black art.
和黑魔法没什么两样
It was very sophisticated and there were few players
它非常依靠经验 也很难找到我们需要的
in the field sort of supplying the materials that we needed.
业内提供这些材料的人士
And so, for us to gain insight
所以我们要获得更加深入了解
into how better to control the color on film,
更优质的控制胶片颜色的办法
it was a real challenge.
实在是一个挑战
So, we went back to first principles.
所以 我们回到了最初的原理
We analyzed the film at a really low level.
我们以非常底层的视角研究胶片
I mean, we kind of stretched and pushed and pulled
我是说 我们又拉又扯胶片
in every possible exposure way possible
组合各种可能的方式和曝光值
and measured everything that we could find
测量我们可以测量的到的东西
about the film until we came to, I guess,
最后我们达到了一种 我猜是
a state where we knew more about how to influence the film
相比卖给我胶片的人
than the people who were selling it to us.
我们更明白如何去影响胶片
We were able to do things with it
我们知道连卖东西的人
that they didn't even know were possible.
都不知道的处理方法
I am communicating with the artists,
我与艺术家
the directors of photography, the lighting leads
摄影指导 首席灯光师
and the folks who are responsible for implementing
以及任何工作室中
the color decisions of the studio.
和颜色决策相关的人交流
And I'm working with them to better understand
我与他们一同工作来更好的了解
what they're trying to achieve.
他们想实现的东西
Often, this is one, two, three years
时常 我的工作要
in advance of them doing the work.
比他们提前个两三年完成
They have an idea in their head of what they'd like to try.
他们脑中出现了一个他们想尝试的东西
It might be something that no one's ever seen before.
也许是以往都没有见过的东西
My job then is to sort of translate those requirements
我的工作大概就是将这些要求转化为
and turn them into a pipeline or a platform
一条流水线或平台
or a set of steps and processes
或是一些步骤和流程
that we can gain confidence is gonna work
让我们有信心能完成它们
when the clock's ticking and we don't have a lot of time
当时间紧凑我们需要
to sort of finish this work
完成工作
or to sorta iterate many times on a creative idea.
或没有时间多次迭代那些创意时
So, I kinda build the foundation of the pieces necessary
所以 我会建立一些必要的基础
to allow those artists to really express themselves
让艺术家们以一种可以复述的方式
in a way that's repeatable.
表达他们的需求
Things that are happening
发生在
in the world of motion picture film.
动画电影中的一切吧
So, on the exhibition side, you go to the cinema
就放映这块来说 如今已经可以
and there's a digital projector today;
在电影院看到激光投影机了
that's how we experience our films on the big screen.
这就是我们在大屏幕上体验电影的方法了
The next generation of digital projectors
下一代的数字投影机
is using red, green, and blue lasers
将使用红色、绿色和蓝色的激光
to illuminate the scene.
照亮荧幕
So, all of a sudden, we can get
所以 突然一下 我们就可以获得
these really, really saturated colors
那些非常非常浓烈的颜色了
way out on the spectral locus.
那是远超色度图可以表示的颜色
So, the most saturated things that humans can perceive,
所以我们可以用这些激光投影仪创造出一些
we can now create some of those with these laser projectors.
人类可以感知到的最浓烈的颜色
And there's also new opportunities, I think,
我想 也有一些新的机遇
for some of our filmmakers to potentially show you colors
让我们的电影制作者们有能力展示出那些
that, quite literally, you've never seen before.
字面意义上的 你从未见过的颜色
Everything that you have a passion for
任何你热衷的事情
has a value in this world.
一定有它存在于世的意义
And people are gonna continue to tell you
人们会不断告诉你
that this is not cool or this is not popular
每没意思或钻牛角尖的事情
or, in my case, it was math and music.
对于我来说可能是数学和音乐
They still aren't necessarily the most socially upheld
它们只是得不到大众的
kind of revered pursuits.
尊重和追求
But you can find a way easily
但你一定能简单地找到一个地方
where that makes a real difference for somebody,
为一些人造成巨大的变化
that you can harness that passion and turn it into something
在那里你可以驾驭着你的热情 把它们变成
that really makes a difference in the world. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
改变世界的工具 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox